Ekpenisi E. Raphael.

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

Gmail | GitHub | LinkedIn | Twitter | Medium | Portfolio

SUMMARY

I'm a full-stack software developer who specializes in using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Tailwind, SCSS JavaScript, React, Redux, Next.JS, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Express.JS, MongoDB, Node.JS, MySQL and Postgresql. I've spent the last several months completely immersed in remote development, building everything from landing pages with frontend technologies to backend with Rails APIs and Express, and have learned the importance of communication, collaboration and teamwork skills.

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux NextJS, HTML5, CSS3, Tailwind, SCSS, SASS and Bootsrap TailwindCSS, Back-End: Ruby, Ruby on Rails, NextJS Server, Postgresql, Mysql, Express.js, MongoDB and Node.js Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Netlify, Herokun, Versel, Mobile/Responsive Web Development, Jest Test, MVC SPA, RWD, RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools Restful API, OOPs, SEO IT Support and WordPress plugins. Professional: Remote pair programming, Source control, Teamwork communication, collaboration and Mentoring.

EXPERIENCE

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

Remote

Full-Stack Web Developer

October 2023 - Present

Sant Ralph magazine — This web app, enables users to post after signing up. It's designed with CSS and React, ensuring SEO friendliness. Moreover, it's been submitted to the Search Console for sitemap and page indexing.

built with Next.js and NextAuth.js.

<u>Todo-List</u> — Designed to help users manage their tasks. Users can create a task, read tasks, update tasks, delete a task, check completed tasks and delete all checked tasks

Built with: HTML, CSS & JavaScript, ES6, REST API and React.js)

Awesome — This website allows users to store each input in their local storage and these inputs can be deleted from the local storage also by clicking on the remove button. This was built using modular JS, and local storage.

Built with: HTML, CSS & JavaScript and Jest unit)

MICROVERSE Remote August 2022 - present

Mentor (Volunteer)

MICROVERSE

- Mentor junior web developers, providing technical support through code reviews.
- Propose improvements to code organisation to improve code quality and overall performance.
- Provide advice and tips on maintaining motivation to maintain longevity in the program.

CYBERSPACE NETWORK LIMITED

Lagos, Nigeria.

Network customer support engineer

Jan 2011 - Dec 2011

Configured and installed applications on laptops for sim card registration for the Visafone network company due to my commitment to duties and vast knowledge of system administration.

EDUCATION

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full-Time

July 2022 - Jun 2023

- Spent 4000+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack front-end and back-end while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Postgresql, JavaScript, React.js, and Redux.js.
- Developed skills in remote pair programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

AUCHI POLYTECHNIC Dec 2007 - July 2010

Nation diplomat, Computer science

- Algorithms, data structures, Networking and Digital electronics.
- Graphics designs such as PowerPoint, Adobe Page Maker, Microsoft Word, Microsoft Excel etc.